Monterrey, Nuevo León

Claudio B Rodríguez

claudiordgz

D +52 1 (81) 13490166

StackOverflow Profile

Objective

I decided to be a Software Developer when optimizing matrix calculations in my TI-89 calculator to make my life easier. My passion for development is in how I am able to improve the quality of life of a person just by making the software faster, lighter, and more robust all at the same time. I program using TDD because it provides me with a continuous flow of production while at the same time adding test coverage. Even though, I have built some UI in WPF, my love resides in the back end of things and making it more powerful, faster, better.

My current interests are mostly related to optimization using every available tool at my disposal. There are hidden savings to discover whether it is through Software Architectures, Algorithm optimizations or Data Structure profiling. Lately, I've been dedicated to studying everything related to the build process, from design to deployment.

Most of my time I try to learn new things to make things faster or keep researching evolutionary computation. Or maybe just learning what and how to optimize everything at my home, or planning my future with my family.

Professional Experience

Epicor Software Project: LaserCat 3 June 2014 - Current

- Allowed utility to check for updates for all of my customers by developing a cross platform C++ utility.
- Created silent installations by migrating installers from exe to msi.
- Reduced production time for installations by creating reusable libraries.
- Added relative position design to WiX Dialogs by creating parsing utilities in C++.

AMI GE Automation & Control Innovation June 2012 - June 2014

Project: DigitARC PX3

- Reduced size of files being logged by %60 using Audio Compression.
- Prevented errors when changes to crucial features of the system were done by automating C++ and Bash/Batch testing mechanism and automating them using CruiseControl.
- Reduced customer support from 6 man-hr average p/week to 2 man-hr p/month average by creating tutorials for repeated configuration errors, creating tools in Python, and creating Unit Tests for common changed parts.
- Created a modify once, publish on different places system for our product manual, automated it in CruiseControl.

ETEX Bash Batch WPF/C#

Tools

- Git
- SVN
- Autotools
- Windows
- Linux
- QNX
- Visual Studio
- WiX Toolset

GE Consumer & Industrial 2008

• Developed 147 scheduled maintenance tasks, one for each equipment, deployed and trained maintenance and production personnel.

• Trained Purchasing Leader, Technology Leader, Maintenance Leader, and Production Leader in the use of PMPro tool so they could maximize their benefits from Preventive Maintenance.

Education

Tec de Monterrey, N.L.

Master in Science with Specialty in Intelligent Systems (2010)

- Member of Professorship of Applied Intelligent Agents in Videogames.
- Specialization in Particle Swarm Optimization and Emergent Behavior Algorithms.

Tec de Monterrey Campus Sonora Norte Mechatronics Engineer (2004-2008) Hermosillo, Son

Projects

Dental Place Access Control

WPF/Net 4.5 Utility to allow to keep up to date records for customer access control.

• Allowed my customer to maintain his brand vision by creating a minimal, and beautiful solution for him.

Phoenix2D Project

Open Source project to allow students to develop their own Player to compete in RoboCup Soccer Simulation. Currently redesigning implementation.

- Created build system using GNU Autotools.
- Created website.
- · Create documentation.

WixRelativeDialogs Project

Open Source project for creating dialogs using relative positioning, allowing for more flexible production times. (Faster is better).

Developed whole functionality, working in adding UI using QT.